STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK BOARD OF TRUSTEES RECORDS (APAP098) 1950-1994
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
State University of New York Board of Trustees Records1950-1994
nam_apap098
State University of New York. Board of Trustees
6.4 processed to date
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
State University of New York, Borad of Trustees Records document the activities of all of the State University of New York campus statewide from
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Organizational Sketch
There is no Organization Sketch
Scope and Content Information
An artificial collection of official records of the State University of New York, a 64 campus statewide system of higher education established under Gov. Thomas E. Dewey in 1948 with Central Administration headquarters in Albany, New York. Includes system-wide planning documents, reports, and other official publications (principally, News), 1958- 1984 & selected Board of Trustees minutes, 1950-70, and policies, 1954-90, and also board member correspondence files kept by the Student Association of the State University of New York (SASU), 1971-81.
The records of the Office of the President (UA-000) include summary minutes of the SUNY Board of Trustees meetings for 1968, 1970-1984. Related collections include: the papers of Donald Blinken (APAP-080)& the records of the State University Construciton (APAP-097)& the records of the State University of New York, University Faculty Senate (APAP-093)& and the records of the Student Association of the State University of New York (SASU) (APAP-046).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1: Meetings, 1950-1980
Series 2: Publications, 1958-1984
Series 3: Corresondence, 1971-1980
Series 4: Chancellors, 1971-1980
Series 5: Subject Files, 1966-1982
Series 6: Annual Reports, 1949-ca. 1965
Series 7: Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1954-1984
Series 1,2,6 and 7 are arranged chronologically. Series 3 and 4 are arranged alphabetically. Series 5 is arranged randomly [neither chronologically nor alphabetically].
Subject and Genre Headings
State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; Ethnic Groups; Education; State University of New York SUNY, Central Administration; Ethnic Groups; Education; Student Association of the State University of New York; State University of New York, Board of Trustees; New York; Meeting; Minutes; Agendas; News; Memos; Reports; Hearings; Issues; News; Correspondence
Container List
- Mettings, 1950-1980; 1; 1.6
  Arranged chronologically.
  The Meetings series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee and business meeting minutes, meeting reports and agendas
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3-8)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, Jan.1969 - June 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, July 1969 - December 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, January 1970 - June 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Minutes and Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Minutes and Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Minutes and Reports, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Minutes Vol.I-II, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meetings, June 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meetings, September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Meetings, October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, September 25,1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, October 23,1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, November 27,1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, December 18,1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, January 22,1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SASU, Board of Trustees, Agenda, February 26,1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, Macrh 26,1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, April 23,1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, May 28,1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, November 26,1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, December 17,1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, February 25,1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, March 24,1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, April 28,1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, May 26,1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, June 27,1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees, Agenda, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Publications, 1958-1984; 2; 1.4
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Washington Reports and News
  - Washington Report, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Washington Report, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Washington Report, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Report, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The News, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The News, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The News, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The News, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The News, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The News, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The News, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The News, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The News, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9-16)
  - The News, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1971-1980; 3; 1
  Arranged alphabetically.
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Correspondence and Memos
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Blinken, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Downey, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Trustees, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Ward, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Wherton, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos, September 1978 - December 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, Memos to Board Members, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos on Politics, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees, Memos on Politics, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Chancellors, 1971-1981; 4; 1
  Arranged alphabetically (Except folder 11).
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Chancellor's records which includes policy planning, information on issues, memos, academic programs, leagal and university affairs
  - Board of Trustees, Associate Chancellor for Health Services, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Associate Chancellor for Policy Planning, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Information on Issues, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Information on Issues, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Information on Issues, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Information on Issues, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Memos, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Memos, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Memos, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor Wharton, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Deputy Chancellor, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Chancellor, Panel Review on Status & Faculty Review, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Vice Chancellor, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Vice Chancellor Acedemic Programs, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Vice Chancellor Legal Affairs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees, Office of Vice Chancellor University Affairs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Subject Files, 1966-1982; 5; 1.4
  Arranged randomly(neither alphabetically nor chronologically)
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Public Meetings & Hearings, Auxilary Services Committee, Reports to Board, issues and politics and as well as State University of New York Student's Trustee issue
  - Board of Trustees, Auxiliary Services Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Background Studies, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Budgets Executive, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SUNY- Student Trustee Issue, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Student Trustee Community College, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SUNY- Student Trustee Issue, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Public Meeting & Hearings, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Public Meeting & Hearings, November 1980 - December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Board of Trustees, Public Meeting & Hearings, Law, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Reports to Board, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Reports to Board, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Reports to Board Special Programs, 1966-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Residence Halls, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Tape-Press Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Issue & Policies, Misc. Vol I-IV, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Issue & Politics, Misc. Vol II-IV, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
- Annual Reports, 1949-ca. 1965; 6; 0.17
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Annual Reports
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 1st Annual Report, January 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 2nd Annual Report, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 3rd Annual Report, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 4th Annual Report, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 5th Annual Report, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 7th Annual Report, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 9th Annual Report, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 11th Annual Report, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees 12th Annual Report, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees Annual Report, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SUNY Board of Trustees Annual Report, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1954-1994; 7; 0.17
  Arranged chronologically (Except folder 2).
  The Publication series consists of State University of New York Board of Trustee's Policies
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1961; 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1956; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1964; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1966; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1968; 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1973; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1975; 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1980; 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1989; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1992; 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Policies of the Board of Trustees, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Revisions to the Policies of the Board of Trustees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)